Hello, everyone and welcome back to another lesson here at EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod的另一节课。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
Katerina And my name is Katerina and today we're
Katerina 我是Katerina，今天我们
talking about a topic very close to my heart, music.
要聊一个我非常感兴趣的话题：音乐。
Marco That's right.
Marco 没错。
We're going to be talking about music and more specifically, we are going to talk about
我们要聊音乐，更具体地说，我们要聊
musical instruments that you would use in a band.
乐队里会用到的乐器。
Katerina All right.
Katerina 好的。
And so some people like to make their own music, get together, hang out, play music
有些人喜欢自己创作音乐，聚在一起，闲逛，一起演奏音乐，
together, so that's what we're talking about today.
这就是我们今天要聊的内容。
We've got a new band that's going to start and before we get going, we've got a word
我们有一个新乐队要组建，在开始之前，我们先来聊一个词，
to talk about and let's check this out in today's vocabulary preview.
看看今天的词汇预览。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
Marco All right.
Marco 好的。
So as I mentioned, we are going to talk about instruments.
就像我提到的，我们要聊乐器。
Katerina Instruments.
Katerina 乐器。
So you could say musical instruments, but what is an instrument generally speaking?
所以你可以说乐器，但一般来说，什么是乐器呢？
Marco Basically, it's similar to a tool, right?
Marco 基本上，它类似于工具，对吧？
So an instrument is something that you use to help you realize a task.
所以乐器是你用来帮助完成某件事的东西。
In this case, musical instruments is more specific, right?
在这种情况下，乐器更具体，对吧？
Katerina Right.
Katerina 对。
So we're talking about things that you use to make music.
所以我们聊的是用来制作音乐的东西。
A piano for example.
比如钢琴。
Marco Is a musical instrument.
Marco 就是一种乐器。
Katerina Or the drums.
Katerina 或者鼓。
Marco All right.
Marco 好的。
So this is what we're going to be looking at today in the dialogues.
这就是我们今天在对话中要关注的内容。
So let's listen to it for the first time.
那么，让我们第一次听一下。
Katerina I'm forming a music band.
Katerina 我正在组建一个乐队。
Marco Do you already know how to play an instrument?
Marco 你已经会演奏乐器了吗？
Katerina Uh, yeah.
Katerina 嗯，是的。
I told you a thousand times that I'm learning to play the drums.
我跟你说过一千次了，我正在学打鼓。
Now that I know how to play well, I would like to form a rock band.
现在我已经打得不错了，我想组建一个摇滚乐队。
Marco Aside from yourself, who are the other members
Marco 除了你自己，乐队里还有哪些
of the band?
成员？
Katerina We have a guy who plays guitar and another
Katerina 我们有一个弹吉他的家伙，还有一个
who plays bass.
弹贝斯的。
Although we still haven't found anyone to be our singer.
不过我们还没找到主唱。
You told me that you had some musical talent, right?
你跟我说过你有点音乐天赋，对吧？
Marco Yes, I'm a singer.
Marco 是的，我是歌手。
Katerina Perfect.
Katerina 完美。
So you can audition this weekend here at my house.
所以这周末你可以来我家试音。
Marco Great.
Marco 太好了。
Wait, here?
等等，这里？
You don't have enough room for the amplifiers, microphones, or even your drums.
你这里放不下放大器、麦克风，甚至你的鼓。
By the way, where do you keep them or practice?
顺便问一下，你把它们放在哪里，或者在哪里练习？
Katerina Dude, what are you talking about?
Katerina 哥们，你在说什么呢？
It's right here.
就在这里啊。
All we need is my Nintendo Wii and we're set.
我们只需要我的任天堂Wii就够了。
Marco All right, we're back.
Marco 好的，我们回来了。
So apparently the band wasn't really a real band.
所以显然这个乐队并不是真正的乐队。
Katerina It wasn't, but I have to say I'm very familiar
Katerina 不是，但我得说我对这个很熟悉，
with this because I have a Nintendo Wii and I often play the game Rock Band so I can sympathize
因为我有一台任天堂Wii，经常玩《摇滚乐队》这个游戏，所以我能理解
with the characters.
这些角色。
Marco So you also have your own band?
Marco 所以你也有自己的乐队？
Katerina I do.
Katerina 是的。
Well, virtually speaking.
嗯，虚拟的。
Marco Virtually.
Marco 虚拟的。
Katerina And I know you do too.
Katerina 而且我知道你也有。
Marco I do too.
Marco 我也有。
That's right.
没错。
We are both fans of this game and this gaming console and that's why it's such a fun dialogue.
我们都是这个游戏和游戏机的粉丝，所以这个对话才这么有趣。
But let's take a look at some of the language that was used in this dialogue in Language
但让我们看看这个对话中使用的一些语言，在语言
Takeaway.
要点部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Katerina Oh man, so I've been in a lot of bands and
Katerina 哦天哪，我参加过很多乐队，
I've been in a lot of musical groups so I can say that the first instrument we want
也参加过很多音乐团体，所以我想说，我们要聊的第一个乐器可能是最烦人的、
to talk about is maybe the most obnoxious, the most loud and hard to listen to.
最吵的、最难听的。
Marco Probably, probably.
Marco 可能吧，可能吧。
And that instrument is the drums.
那就是鼓。
So the drums, it's plural because you have many drums, right?
所以鼓是复数，因为你有多个鼓，对吧？
Katerina Right.
Katerina 对。
You don't just have the dum-dum-dum-dum, the bass drum.
你不仅仅有咚咚咚的低音鼓。
You have many different drums together and so we could also call this a drum set.
你有许多不同的鼓组合在一起，所以我们也可以称之为一套鼓。
Marco A drum set.
Marco 一套鼓。
All right, so why don't we listen to an example of what a drum set sounds like.
好的，那我们听一下一套鼓的声音示例吧。
All right, we're back.
好的，我们回来了。
So I think that's clear.
所以我想这很清楚了。
Moving on to our next instrument.
接下来看下一个乐器。
Katerina This one's maybe the most popular for young
Katerina 这个可能是年轻人最常开始学的，
people to start because you can play pretty much anything with it and it's also good for
因为你可以用它演奏几乎任何东西，而且也很适合
sing-alongs.
跟着唱。
Marco Right, and that instrument is the guitar.
Marco 对，那就是吉他。
Katerina Can you play the guitar?
Katerina 你会弹吉他吗？
Marco No, I can't.
Marco 不，我不会。
I actually wish I would have learned but I never got around to it.
我其实希望我学过，但我一直没抽出时间。
Katerina Well, this is a really beautiful instrument
Katerina 嗯，这是一种非常漂亮的乐器，
and there are many different ways to play it but generally, it's either wooden with
有很多不同的演奏方式，但一般来说，要么是木制的带一些弦，
some strings or electric so it's plastic with some metal strings.
要么是电的，塑料的带金属弦。
Marco Right, exactly.
Marco 对，没错。
So they have a different sound but why don't we listen to an example of what a guitar sounds
所以它们有不同的声音，但我们听一下吉他的声音示例吧。
like.
All right, so great example of a guitar, pretty clear.
好的，很好的吉他示例，很清楚。
What's our next instrument?
下一个乐器是什么？
Katerina The bass and this one, it doesn't look like
Katerina 贝斯，这个单词拼写是B-A-S-S，
the word that's written, B-A-S-S, so we say bass.
但发音是bass。
And it's actually a very low instrument.
它实际上是一种很低沉的乐器。
It's usually used to help keep the rhythm.
通常用来帮助保持节奏。
Marco All right, so it's similar to a guitar, right?
Marco 好的，所以它类似于吉他，对吧？
Katerina Very.
Katerina 非常像。
Marco It's the same form but as you say, it's lower
Marco 形状一样，但就像你说的，它更低，
and it makes a lower sound.
发出更低的声音。
Katerina Exactly.
Katerina 没错。
Marco All right, so let's listen to an example of
Marco 好的，那我们听一下贝斯的
a bass now.
示例吧。
All right, pretty clear.
好的，很清楚。
Moving on to our next word, we have an amplifier.
接下来看下一个词，我们有放大器。
Katerina Okay, so amplifier, an amplifier is a thing.
Katerina 好的，放大器，放大器是一个东西。
It's usually a box that we plug in, it's electric or it's electronic and it's a tool to make
通常是一个盒子，我们插上电，它是电动的或电子的，是一种工具，用来让
electrical instruments like the electric guitar or the electric bass louder.
电乐器，比如电吉他或电贝斯，声音更大。
Marco Right, exactly.
Marco 对，没错。
So an amplifier is any device that makes a sound become louder.
所以放大器是任何能让声音变大的设备。
Katerina Exactly.
Katerina 没错。
Marco All right.
Marco 好的。
Katerina So this is really important for rock bands
Katerina 所以这对全世界的摇滚乐队
the world over.
来说非常重要。
Marco Very good.
Marco 很好。
Our next instrument or actually more of a tool is very useful for the singer.
我们的下一个乐器，或者更确切地说是一个工具，对歌手非常有用。
Katerina Yeah, and it actually goes with the amplifier
Katerina 是的，而且它在很多方面和放大器
in many ways because the microphone, this is our next word, the microphone is something
是配套的，因为麦克风，这是我们的下一个词，麦克风是某种东西。
that you use to sing into to make your voice louder.
你用来对着唱歌、让声音更响的东西。
So right now, Marco, you and I are both using microphones.
所以现在，马可，你和我都在用麦克风。
Marco Exactly.
马可：没错。
So a microphone.
所以是麦克风。
Very good.
很好。
And we have one last word and this is a verb, to audition.
我们还有最后一个词，这是一个动词，试演。
Katerina All right, to audition.
卡特琳娜：好的，试演。
So to audition means to show someone your talent, all right?
试演的意思是向别人展示你的才华，明白吗？
So oftentimes when you start a play or an opera or a musical group, you want to have
所以通常当你开始排演一部话剧、歌剧或组建一个音乐团体时，你会想要进行
auditions.
试演。
You want to audition people to see how much talent they have.
你想通过试演来考察人们有多少才华。
Marco All right.
马可：好的。
So it's basically an opportunity to demonstrate your skills and abilities.
所以这基本上是一个展示你技能和能力的机会。
Katerina Exactly.
卡特琳娜：没错。
Marco So a job interview wouldn't really be an audition.
马可：所以工作面试不算是试演。
Katerina No, a job interview has its own word.
卡特琳娜：不，工作面试有它自己的词。
But here we're talking about your singing ability, your acting ability, your reading
但这里我们说的是你的唱歌能力、表演能力、阅读能力，
ability and sometimes we even have auditions here at EnglishPod to see how comfortable
有时我们甚至在EnglishPod也会进行试演，看看人们
people are on the microphone.
在麦克风前有多自在。
It's a way to have people show what they've got.
这是一种让人们展示自己本事的方式。
Marco Very good.
马可：很好。
All right.
好的。
So a lot of interesting words here, many instruments.
这里有很多有趣的词，很多乐器。
I think it's time for us to listen to our dialogue again.
我想是时候再听一遍我们的对话了。
We're going to slow it down a little bit and we'll be right back.
我们会放慢一点速度，马上回来。
Katerina I'm forming a music band.
卡特琳娜：我正在组建一个乐队。
Marco Do you already know how to play an instrument?
马可：你已经会演奏乐器了吗？
Katerina Yeah, I told you a thousand times that I'm
卡特琳娜：是啊，我跟你说过一千次了，我正在
learning to play the drums.
学打鼓。
Now that I know how to play well, I would like to form a rock band.
现在我已经打得不错了，我想组建一个摇滚乐队。
Marco Aside from yourself, who are the other members
马可：除了你自己，乐队还有哪些
of the band?
成员？
Katerina We have a guy who plays guitar and another
卡特琳娜：我们有一个弹吉他的，还有一个
who plays bass.
弹贝斯的。
Although we still haven't found anyone to be our singer.
不过我们还没找到主唱。
You told me that you had some musical talent, right?
你跟我说过你有点音乐天赋，对吧？
Marco Yes, I'm a singer.
马可：是的，我是歌手。
Katerina Perfect.
卡特琳娜：完美。
So you can audition this weekend here at my house.
那这周末你可以来我家试演。
Marco Great.
马可：太好了。
Wait here.
等等。
You don't have enough room for the amplifiers, microphones or even your drums.
你家没有足够空间放音箱、麦克风，甚至你的鼓。
By the way, where do you keep them or practice?
顺便问一下，你把它们放在哪里或者在哪里练习？
Katerina Dude, what are you talking about?
卡特琳娜：哥们，你在说什么呢？
It's right here.
就在这儿啊。
All we need is my Nintendo Wii and we're set.
我们只需要我的任天堂Wii就万事俱备了。
Stan Alright, we're back.
斯坦：好了，我们回来了。
So moving on with our lesson, why don't we take a look now at some phrases in Fluency
那么继续我们的课程，现在我们来看看“流利度构建”中的一些
Builder.
短语。
Katerina Fluency Builder.
卡特琳娜：流利度构建。
Stan Alright, so on Fluency Builder we have four
斯坦：好的，在流利度构建中我们有四个
phrases.
短语。
What's the first one?
第一个是什么？
Katerina Well, this first phrase is really important,
卡特琳娜：嗯，第一个短语非常重要，
Marco, because we're talking about bands and starting bands.
马可，因为我们在谈论乐队和组建乐队。
And so there's often a phrase we use to describe this.
我们经常用一个短语来描述这个。
We say to form a band.
我们说“组建乐队”。
Stan Alright, so you form a band.
斯坦：好的，所以你组建一个乐队。
Katerina It's like forming something.
卡特琳娜：这就像在塑造什么东西。
To form is to shape it, to make it look like something that you want.
“组建”就是塑造它，让它变成你想要的样子。
And so we can form artistic projects also.
我们也可以组建艺术项目。
But here we're forming a band.
但这里我们在组建一个乐队。
We're choosing people to bring together to make great music.
我们挑选人聚在一起，创作美妙的音乐。
Stan Alright, so we can say form a band or you
斯坦：好的，所以我们可以说“组建乐队”，或者
can say as well, start a band.
也可以说“成立乐队”。
Alright.
好的。
So we're forming a band and well, his friend was surprised that the other guy knew how
所以我们在组建一个乐队，而他的朋友很惊讶另一个人会
to play an instrument.
演奏乐器。
So he said, I've told you a thousand times.
所以他说：“我跟你说过一千次了。”
Katerina Wait, wait.
卡特琳娜：等等，等等。
So he told him one thousand times.
所以他跟他说了一千次。
Stan No, not literally.
斯坦：不，不是字面意思。
Katerina I play an instrument.
卡特琳娜：我会演奏乐器。
I play an instrument.
我会演奏乐器。
Stan Right.
斯坦：对。
This is a phrase and it's a little bit of an exaggeration to emphasize that I've told
这是一个短语，有点夸张，用来强调我已经告诉过你
you many, many times already.
很多很多次了。
Katerina Great.
卡特琳娜：太好了。
So this is something we say when we're trying to exaggerate like Marco said or to really
所以这是我们在试图夸张时说的话，就像马可说的，或者真的
emphasize the point that like I've told you this before.
强调一点，比如我之前告诉过你。
So mothers often use it.
所以妈妈们经常用这个。
I feel like we talk about mothers a lot here.
我觉得我们在这里经常提到妈妈。
Mothers often use this phrase when kids do something wrong.
妈妈们在孩子做错事时经常用这个短语。
They say, I've told you a thousand times not to wear your shoes in the house.
她们会说：“我跟你说过一千次了，别穿着鞋进屋。”
Stan Exactly.
斯坦：没错。
So it is a great phrase to really make your point that you've said something many, many
所以这是一个很好的短语，用来强调你已经说过很多
times.
很多次了。
Moving on, we have a kind of like a conjunction that you can use and it's by the way to change
继续，我们有一个像连词一样的词，你可以用它来
the topic maybe.
改变话题，就是“顺便说一下”。
By the way.
顺便说一下。
Katerina By the way.
卡特琳娜：顺便说一下。
And so by the way, we keep these words together.
所以“顺便说一下”，我们把这些词放在一起。
It's a fixed phrase.
这是一个固定短语。
By the way is something we add on.
“顺便说一下”是我们附加的东西。
So I say, you know, today I went to school and I saw a lot of people.
所以我说，你知道，今天我去学校，看到了很多人。
Oh, by the way, John says hi.
哦，顺便说一下，约翰问好。
All right, so while I'm talking about this, I want to add that this thing happened or
好的，所以当我在说这个的时候，我想补充说这件事发生了，或者
that this person said something.
那个人说了什么。
Stan Exactly.
斯坦：没错。
So it is, it's a conjunction, right, to put together two different ideas.
所以它是一个连词，对吧，用来连接两个不同的想法。
By the way, or you can start off your sentence with it.
“顺便说一下”，或者你可以用它开头句子。
By the way, how is the new house?
顺便问一下，新房子怎么样？
Katerina Oh, because it's like, it's like saying, oh,
卡特琳娜：哦，因为它就像，就像在说，哦，
this thought just came into my head.
这个想法突然出现在我脑海里。
By the way.
顺便说一下。
Stan Right, right.
斯坦：对，对。
And our last phrase on Fluency Builder is we are set.
我们在流利度构建中的最后一个短语是“我们准备好了”。
Katerina All right, all we need is my Nintendo Wii
卡特琳娜：好的，我们只需要我的任天堂Wii
and we are set.
就准备好了。
Stan All right, so what are we set?
斯坦：好的，所以我们准备好了什么？
We are set.
我们准备好了。
Katerina All right, we are set is another one of those
卡特琳娜：好的，“我们准备好了”是另一个
phrases that's fixed and it literally it means and we are ready to start.
固定短语，字面意思是“我们准备好开始了”。
We're ready to go.
我们准备就绪。
Stan And everything is ready.
斯坦：而且一切都准备好了。
Katerina Yeah, we don't need anything else.
卡特琳娜：是的，我们不需要别的了。
And so Marco, I could say to you, just bring, just bring the salad to the table and we're
所以马可，我可以对你说，只要把沙拉端上桌，我们就
set.
准备好了。
We're ready to eat.
我们准备开吃了。
Stan All right.
斯坦：好的。
And I think we're set to listen to our dialogue for the last time.
我想我们准备好最后一次听对话了。
And we'll be right back and talk a little bit more about this great topic.
我们马上回来，再聊聊这个精彩的话题。
I'm forming a music band.
我正在组建一个乐队。
Do you already know how to play an instrument?
你已经会演奏乐器了吗？
Yeah, I told you a thousand times that I'm learning to play the drums.
是啊，我跟你说过一千遍了，我正在学打鼓。
Now that I know how to play well, I would like to form a rock band.
既然我现在打得不错了，我想组个摇滚乐队。
Aside from yourself, who are the other members of the band?
除了你自己，乐队还有哪些成员？
We have a guy who plays guitar and another who plays bass.
我们有一个弹吉他的，还有一个弹贝斯的。
Although we still haven't found anyone to be our singer.
不过我们还没找到主唱。
You told me that you had some musical talent, right?
你跟我说过你有点音乐天赋，对吧？
Yes, I'm a singer.
是的，我是歌手。
Perfect.
完美。
So you can audition this weekend here at my house.
那你这周末可以来我家试音。
Great.
太好了。
Wait here.
在这儿等着。
You don't have enough room for the amplifiers, microphones or even your drums.
你这里空间不够放音箱、麦克风，甚至连你的鼓都放不下。
By the way, where do you keep them or practice?
顺便问一下，你把它们放在哪儿，或者你在哪儿练习？
Dude, what are you talking about?
哥们，你在说什么呢？
It's right here.
就在这儿啊。
All we need is my Nintendo Wii and we're set.
我们只需要我的任天堂Wii，就万事俱备了。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So rock band now.
所以现在是摇滚乐队的话题。
I know that you play a real instrument, not only instruments on the Wii.
我知道你演奏的是真正的乐器，不只是Wii上的乐器。
True.
没错。
What do you play?
你演奏什么？
I play the trumpet.
我吹小号。
I was classically trained.
我受过古典训练。
I started when I was 10.
我从十岁开始学的。
Now is this the trumpet that has the three buttons on the top?
是那种顶部有三个按钮的小号吗？
Yes, three pistons.
是的，三个活塞。
Three pistons.
三个活塞。
Because there's another one that doesn't, right?
因为还有一种没有三个，对吧？
There's one that has four pistons.
有一种有四个活塞。
It's a piccolo trumpet, has four.
那是高音小号，有四个活塞。
And there's one that's large and it slides in and out and that's a trombone.
还有一种大的，能伸缩的，那是长号。
That's much lower.
那个音调低得多。
Right, right.
对，对。
But the trumpet is kind of a mid-range instrument.
但小号算是中音域的乐器。
It can go quite high and a little bit low.
它能吹得很高，也能稍微低一点。
And it's brass, it's not wood.
它是铜管乐器，不是木管。
It's made of a metal.
它是金属做的。
Right.
对。
It looks like gold, right?
它看起来像金色的，对吧？
Right.
对。
Alright, so you play the trumpet.
好吧，所以你吹小号。
Did you play in a band or in a school or college?
你在乐队、学校或大学里演奏过吗？
In middle school and high school, I played in bands and orchestras.
在初中和高中，我在乐队和管弦乐团里演奏过。
And in college, I played in orchestra and I've also played in rock bands because sometimes
在大学里，我在管弦乐团演奏过，也参加过摇滚乐队，因为有时候
people want to, you know...
人们想，你知道……
Have a trumpet in the background.
让小号在背景里出现。
Have a trumpet and go a little crazy.
让小号来点疯狂的感觉。
Nice.
不错。
Interesting.
有意思。
This is interesting because I'm sure a lot of our users out there actually play instruments
这很有意思，因为我确信我们很多用户实际上会演奏乐器，
and maybe a lot of them are also good at it.
也许很多人还很擅长。
So come to EnglishPod.com, leave your questions and comments and let us know if you play any
所以来EnglishPod.com，留下你的问题和评论，告诉我们你是否演奏任何
instruments or maybe some strange instruments like the xylophone.
乐器，或者像木琴这样奇怪的乐器。
Or if you like to play We Rock Band because we certainly do and we can support you on
或者如果你喜欢玩《摇滚乐队》游戏，因为我们肯定喜欢，而且我们可以在这方面
that one.
支持你。
We can give you some tips.
我们可以给你一些建议。
Yeah.
是啊。
Alright, so we'll see you guys there.
好了，那我们到时候见。
Until next time.
下次再见。
Bye everyone.
大家再见。
Thanks for listening.
感谢收听。